Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're at a party.
今天我们正在一个派对上。
Yeah, this is a great, exciting, fun, energetic lesson.
是的，这是一节很棒、激动人心、有趣、充满活力的课程。
We're at the biggest party in the world, Carnival in Rio.
我们在世界上最大的派对上——里约狂欢节。
Okay, so Rio, this is the name of a city, right?
好的，所以Rio，这是一个城市名，对吧？
Yeah, this is a city in Brazil called Rio de Janeiro.
是的，这是巴西的一个城市，叫里约热内卢。
So Rio de Janeiro.
所以是里约热内卢。
Yeah, different pronunciations, right?
是的，发音不同，对吧？
Yeah, yours sounds a lot more, I don't know, authentic than mine.
嗯，你的发音听起来比我更地道，我也说不上来。
So we sometimes refer to it as Rio just to make it shorter.
所以我们有时简称它为Rio，这样更短。
Yeah, I think that's actually the most common way it's referred to in English.
是的，我觉得这实际上是英语中最常见的叫法。
Yeah, Rio.
是的，Rio。
It's just like if you would say Los Angeles, you would say LA.
就像你说洛杉矶，你会说LA一样。
Yeah, or if you're talking about Kuala Lumpur, you might say KL.
是的，或者如果你说吉隆坡，你可能会说KL。
Yeah.
是的。
Same idea.
同样的道理。
Okay, so we have some words that we're going to preview before we listen to our dialogue.
好的，在我们听对话之前，先预览一些单词。
So let's start with vocabulary preview.
那么我们从词汇预览开始。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, in vocabulary preview, we have one word, Sambadrome.
好的，在词汇预览中，我们有一个词，Sambadrome。
Sambadrome.
Sambadrome。
This is actually a building.
这实际上是一个建筑。
So it's a proper noun, not a common noun, right?
所以它是一个专有名词，不是普通名词，对吧？
No, it's not really a common noun.
不，它不算是普通名词。
It's a proper noun, but it is a building.
它是一个专有名词，但它是一个建筑。
And what happens in this building?
这个建筑里会发生什么？
Basically, it's very similar to a stadium, but each end isn't closed off.
基本上，它很像一个体育场，但两端不是封闭的。
So you have stands on one side and stands on the other.
所以一边有看台，另一边也有看台。
And you have like a little street in the middle.
中间有一条像小街道一样的地方。
So you can sit down and you can watch people parade or walk by, and you can see the dancers
所以你可以坐下来，观看人们游行或走过，你可以看到舞者
and everything.
和所有的一切。
And so what is it used for?
那它是用来做什么的？
The Sambadrome is used so that the Samba schools can present their dances and their dancers
Sambadrome是用来让桑巴舞学校向评委和所有想看他们跳桑巴舞的人展示他们的舞蹈、舞者
and their costumes to judges and all the people that want to watch them dance Samba.
和服装的。
Okay, so you've been using this word a lot.
好的，你一直在用这个词。
Samba.
Samba。
What is this?
这是什么？
It's a dance that Brazil is famous for.
这是巴西著名的舞蹈。
It's a very fast dance, a lot of hip movements, a lot of...
一种非常快的舞蹈，有很多臀部动作，很多……
It's very fast, but it's very, very nice.
非常快，但非常非常好看。
And the music is based with many different type of tropical instruments.
音乐基于许多不同类型的热带乐器。
So it's really, really fun.
所以真的非常有趣。
Can you Samba?
你会跳桑巴舞吗？
I can Samba a little bit.
我会跳一点点。
It's kind of hard.
有点难。
It's trickier than what it seems.
比看起来要棘手。
Okay, well, we're actually going to hear some Samba music in the dialogue, right?
好的，我们实际上会在对话中听到一些桑巴音乐，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And we're going to hear some Samba that is actually used during Carnival.
我们会听到一些在狂欢节期间使用的桑巴音乐。
Okay, so let's go to Rio now and listen to some Samba.
好的，那我们现在就去里约，听一些桑巴音乐吧。
I can't believe we're here.
真不敢相信我们在这里。
Carnival in Rio.
里约狂欢节。
Seriously.
说真的。
This is like a once in a lifetime opportunity.
这真是千载难逢的机会。
Can you believe it?
你能相信吗？
We're here at the biggest party in the world.
我们在这里，在世界上最大的派对上。
I know.
我知道。
We're so lucky we found tickets for the Sambadrome.
我们真幸运，找到了Sambadrome的门票。
Good thing we found that ticket scalper.
还好我们找到了那个票贩子。
Look, it's starting.
看，开始了。
Wow, this is amazing.
哇，太棒了。
Look at how many dancers there are.
看看有多少舞者。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
The costumes are so colorful.
服装真鲜艳。
This is so cool.
太酷了。
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious
这里写着，现在跳舞的学校是里约最古老、最负盛名的
Samba schools in Rio.
桑巴舞学校之一。
No kidding.
真的吗。
Look at them.
看看他们。
They're amazing.
他们太棒了。
Look at that girl on top of that float.
看那个站在花车顶上的女孩。
She must be the Carnival Queen.
她一定是狂欢节女王。
Go over there so I can get a picture of you.
到那边去，我给你拍张照片。
Okay.
好的。
Hurry up.
快点。
Take the picture.
拍照。
Come dance with us.
来和我们一起跳舞吧。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
No, I can't.
不，我不会。
Really, I don't know how to dance.
真的，我不会跳舞。
Honey, I'll see you later.
亲爱的，待会儿见。
Patrick, don't just leave me here.
Patrick，别把我丢在这里。
All right.
好吧。
What a lucky guy.
真是个幸运的家伙。
He got asked out to dance by a beautiful Brazilian Samba dancer.
他被一个美丽的巴西桑巴舞者邀请去跳舞。
I know.
我知道。
I don't think his wife was very happy though.
不过我觉得他妻子不太高兴。
Well, we've got some language about Carnival in Rio, right?
嗯，我们有一些关于里约狂欢节的语言点，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So let's look at that now with Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
Our first word on Language Takeaway today, ticket scalper.
今天语言要点的第一个词，ticket scalper。
Ticket scalper.
Ticket scalper。
This is actually a job title, I think.
这实际上是一个职位名称，我觉得。
Maybe not a totally legal job title.
可能不是一个完全合法的职位名称。
Exactly.
没错。
So what does a ticket scalper do?
那票贩子是做什么的？
Basically this person will sell tickets at a higher price to people who don't have tickets.
基本上，这种人会把票以更高的价格卖给没有票的人。
Okay.
好的。
So he buys like 100 tickets and goes and stands outside of the Samba Dome or the...
所以他买比如100张票，然后站在Samba Dome或……
Stadium.
体育场外面。
And he sells them for like twice the price, right?
然后以两倍的价格卖出去，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
Yeah, that's a ticket scalper.
是的，那就是票贩子。
So basically they come in handy sometimes because you want to go to a concert or something
所以基本上，他们有时候挺有用的，因为你想去音乐会什么的
and you don't have tickets, you got to turn to them, right?
但没有票，你就得找他们，对吧？
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Our next word, prestigious.
下一个词，prestigious。
Prestigious.
Prestigious。
Now, this is a very nice word, prestigious.
这是一个很好的词，prestigious。
Before we explain anything, let's listen to some examples.
在我们解释之前，先听一些例子。
Example 1.
例子一。
Harvard University is one of the most prestigious schools in North America.
哈佛大学是北美最负盛名的学校之一。
Example 2.
例子二。
The Academy Award is the most prestigious prize an actor can get in the film industry.
奥斯卡奖是电影行业演员能获得的最负盛名的奖项。
Example 3.
例子三。
He worked really hard and now he is a very prestigious heart surgeon.
他工作非常努力，现在是一位非常有名望的心脏外科医生。
I can see that when something is prestigious, it's really well-respected, right?
我能看出，当某样东西是prestigious时，它非常受尊敬，对吧？
It's well-known, well-respected.
它很有名，很受尊敬。
And if you are part of this thing, you can feel a sense of pride.
如果你是这个事物的一部分，你会感到自豪。
Right.
对。
Prestige.
Prestige。
Okay, now let's take a look at our last word, float.
好的，现在我们来看最后一个词，float。
Float.
Float。
Now, this doesn't mean like to float in water, right?
这个不是指在水里漂浮的意思，对吧？
No, this is a noun, not a verb.
不，这是名词，不是动词。
It's kind of hard to describe, actually.
实际上有点难描述。
Yeah, it is hard to describe.
是的，确实难描述。
A float is something that you commonly see in parades.
Float是你在游行中常见的东西。
Right.
对。
So, it'd be like a car, but you can't really see the car.
它就像一辆车，但你几乎看不到车本身。
No, because it's covered with decorations.
不，因为它被装饰物覆盖了。
With big decorations and it's made to look like an artificial island.
有大型装饰，被做成像一个人工岛屿的样子。
Yeah, or a tree maybe.
是的，或者可能是一棵树。
So you have people standing on there and dancing or waving.
所以有人站在上面跳舞或挥手。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
We'll definitely post a picture of a float on our comment section so you could see what
我们一定会在评论区贴一张花车的图片，这样你就能看到
a float looks like.
花车是什么样子了。
Right.
对。
Now, let's listen to our dialogue again.
现在，我们再听一遍对话。
We're going to slow it down a little bit so you can understand all of these words we've
我们会放慢一点速度，这样你就能理解我们刚才讲的所有这些词了。
just talked about.
I can't believe we're here.
真不敢相信我们在这里。
Carnival in Rio.
里约狂欢节。
Seriously.
说真的。
This is like a once in a lifetime opportunity.
这真是千载难逢的机会。
Can you believe it?
你能相信吗？
We're here at the biggest party in the world.
我们在这里，在世界上最大的派对上。
I know.
我知道。
We're so lucky that we found tickets for the Samba Drome.
我们真幸运，找到了Samba Drome的门票。
Good thing we found that ticket scalper.
还好我们找到了那个票贩子。
Look, it's starting.
看，开始了。
Wow.
哇。
This is amazing.
太棒了。
Look at how many dancers there are.
看看有多少舞者。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
The costumes are so colorful.
服装真鲜艳。
This is so cool.
太酷了。
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious
这里写着，现在跳舞的学校是里约最古老、最负盛名的
Samba schools in Rio.
桑巴舞学校之一。
No kidding.
真的吗。
Look at them.
看看他们。
They're amazing.
他们太棒了。
Look at that girl on top of that float.
看那个站在花车顶上的女孩。
She must be the Carnival Queen.
她一定是狂欢节女王。
Move over there so I can get a picture of you.
到那边去，我给你拍张照片。
Okay.
好的。
Hurry up.
快点。
Take the picture.
拍照。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
No, I can't.
不，我不会。
No.
不。
Really, I don't know how to dance.
真的，我不会跳舞。
Honey, I'll see you later.
亲爱的，待会儿见。
Patrick, don't just leave me here.
Patrick，别把我丢在这里。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, I think we should take a look at some of the phrases.
现在，我觉得我们应该看看一些短语。
Yeah, let's go to Fluency Builder.
是的，我们去流利度构建部分吧。
All right.
好的。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
So we have this phrase, once in a lifetime.
我们有一个短语，once in a lifetime。
Once in a lifetime.
Once in a lifetime。
So this is an expression you would use to say that it doesn't happen very often.
这是一个表达，用来表示某事不常发生。
Yeah, it's a really special event.
是的，这是一个非常特别的事件。
So like a once in a lifetime opportunity.
这就像是一生一次的机会。
Or a once in a lifetime chance.
或者是一生一次的机遇。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
Once in a lifetime.
一生一次。
Let's look at our next phrase, good thing.
我们来看看下一个短语，“good thing”。
Good thing.
好事。
So we have some examples for good thing.
所以我们有一些关于“good thing”的例子。
Why don't we listen to them and then we'll come back.
不如我们先听听这些例子，然后再回来讨论。
Example 1.
例子1。
Good thing I studied for my exam.
幸好我复习了考试。
It was really hard.
考试真的很难。
Example 2.
例子2。
It's a good thing I brought my umbrella.
幸好我带了伞。
It rained the whole day.
下了一整天的雨。
Example 3.
例子3。
It's a good thing that I bought my house before the prices went up.
幸好我在房价上涨之前买了房子。
Good thing I had money in my wallet.
幸好我钱包里有钱。
You're happy you had money in your wallet.
你很高兴钱包里有钱。
You could also maybe use it as a negative, right?
你也可以把它用在否定句里，对吧？
Like good thing I didn't go.
比如“幸好我没去”。
Right.
对。
I'm happy I didn't go because it was terrible.
我很高兴我没去，因为那太糟糕了。
Okay.
好的。
Good thing.
好事。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好了。
Now let's take a look at our last word, no kidding.
现在我们来看看最后一个词，“no kidding”。
No kidding.
不开玩笑。
Okay, so many of you probably already know this word kidding, right?
好的，你们很多人可能已经知道“kidding”这个词，对吧？
Yeah, it means joking.
是的，意思是开玩笑。
Yeah, I'm joking.
是的，我在开玩笑。
Just kidding.
开玩笑的。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
But if I would say no kidding.
但如果我说“no kidding”。
You're saying like, yeah, I totally agree with you.
你是在说，嗯，我完全同意你。
Right.
对。
I agree with you.
我同意你。
I know you are.
我知道你是认真的。
I know you're being serious.
I know it's true.
我知道这是真的。
Yeah.
是的。
So I could say, wow, this restaurant is really expensive.
所以我可以这样说：哇，这家餐厅真贵。
No kidding.
可不是嘛。
Yeah.
是的。
So you would agree like, yeah, for real.
所以你会表示同意，比如，嗯，确实如此。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好了。
So this term no kidding is slang, right?
所以这个术语“no kidding”是俚语，对吧？
It's a little bit informal.
它有点非正式。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again for the third time and then we'll come back
那我们再听一遍对话，第三遍，然后回来
and talk about Brazil.
聊聊巴西。
I can't believe we're here.
真不敢相信我们在这儿。
Carnival in Rio.
里约的狂欢节。
Seriously.
真的。
This is like a once in a lifetime opportunity.
这就像是一生一次的机会。
Can you believe it?
你能相信吗？
We're here at the biggest party in the world.
我们来到了世界上最大的派对。
I know.
我知道。
We're so lucky we found time to do this.
我们真幸运能抽出时间来做这件事。
Good thing we found that ticket scalper.
幸好我们找到了那个票贩子。
Look, it's starting.
看，开始了。
Wow.
哇。
This is amazing.
太棒了。
Look at how many dancers there are.
看看有多少舞者。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
The costumes are so colorful.
服装真鲜艳。
This is so cool.
太酷了。
It says here that the school that is dancing now is one of the oldest and most prestigious
这里写着，现在跳舞的学校是里约最古老、最负盛名的
samba schools in Rio.
桑巴舞学校之一。
No kidding.
可不是嘛。
Look at them.
看看他们。
They're amazing.
他们太棒了。
Look at that girl on top of that float.
看那个花车顶上的女孩。
She's so beautiful.
她真漂亮。
Look at that float.
看那个花车。
She must be the carnival queen.
她一定是狂欢节女王。
Go over there so I can get a picture of you.
到那边去，我给你拍张照片。
Okay.
好的。
Hurry up.
快点。
Take the picture.
拍照吧。
Come dance with us.
来和我们一起跳舞吧。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
No, I can't.
不，我不行。
Really, I don't know how to dance.
真的，我不会跳舞。
Honey, I'll see you later.
亲爱的，待会儿见。
Patrick, don't just leave me here.
帕特里克，别把我丢在这儿。
Woo!
呜！
All right, Marco, so carnival, it's a Brazilian celebration, right?
好了，马可，所以狂欢节是巴西的庆祝活动，对吧？
It's very popular in all Latin America.
它在整个拉丁美洲都很流行。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah, but Brazilian carnival is very, very special.
是的，但巴西的狂欢节非常非常特别。
Okay, so what are they celebrating?
好的，那他们在庆祝什么？
So basically, it's the beginning of Lent, which is this period of time in the Catholic
基本上，这是四旬期的开始，这是天主教
religion right before Easter.
复活节前的一段时间。
Right.
对。
But carnival in Brazil is very special because of all the dancing and all of this and costumes
但巴西的狂欢节非常特别，因为所有的舞蹈、服装
and everything.
和一切。
Yeah, well, from the dialogue, it sounds really wild and crazy.
是的，从对话来看，听起来很狂野和疯狂。
So what happens?
那会发生什么？
Well, it definitely is really amazing and it's just basically a lot of samba music and
嗯，它确实非常棒，基本上就是很多桑巴音乐和
partying and it's really nice and especially to be able to see something so spectacular.
派对，真的很棒，尤其是能看到如此壮观的东西。
It's like hundreds and thousands of dancers in the samba drum and they're parading down
就像成百上千的舞者在桑巴鼓点中，穿着服装
in their costumes and in floats.
在花车上游行。
So it's a very, very special event.
所以这是一个非常非常特别的活动。
All right, so it sounds like a lot of fun.
好的，听起来很有趣。
I want to hear from our listeners.
我想听听听众们的意见。
Yeah, for sure.
是的，当然。
We have a lot of listeners from Brazil and carnival is not only celebrated in Rio.
我们有很多来自巴西的听众，狂欢节不仅在里约庆祝。
It's also in Sao Paulo, in Pernambuco, in Bahia, and it's a little bit different in
也在圣保罗、伯南布哥、巴伊亚，每个地方
each place.
都略有不同。
So it's not just a thing of Rio.
所以不只是里约的事。
It's just more popular there.
只是那里更流行。
Is there a samba drum in each city?
每个城市都有桑巴鼓队吗？
Yeah, there is a samba drum in Sao Paulo.
是的，圣保罗有桑巴鼓队。
Oh, cool.
哦，酷。
Yeah.
是的。
Let us know if you've ever been to carnival or how you celebrate it in your hometown or
告诉我们你是否去过狂欢节，或者你在家乡或
in your city.
城市里如何庆祝。
Yeah, come to our website, EnglishPod.com and leave us your comments all about carnival.
是的，来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你关于狂欢节的评论。
Exactly.
没错。
And everyone, be sure to come because we're going to post some videos of what samba is
大家一定要来，因为我们会发布一些桑巴舞的视频
like and some photos so you can get an idea of this really interesting Brazilian celebration.
和照片，这样你们就能了解这个非常有趣的巴西庆祝活动。
Okay, everyone.
好了，各位。
Thanks for listening and until next time.
感谢收听，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。